Numbers that suit or that do not suit with other numbers 
  
  
  
  
  
  
  
  
  
  
        
  
  
Numbers that suit mutually Numbers that do not suit mutually 
1 |3,4,5,9 6, 8 (2, 7, 50%) 
2 | 3,5, 6,7 4, 9 (1, 8, 50%) 
3 |1,2,4,8,9 5, 6, 7 
4 |1,3,6,7 2, 5, 8 (9, 50%) 
5 | 1,2, 6, 8,9 3, 4, 7 
6 | 2,4,5,7,8 1, 3 9, 50%) 
7 |2,4,6 3, 5, 8, 9 (1, 50%) 
8 |3,5,6,9 1, 4, 7 (2, 50%) 
9 | 1,3,5,8 2,7 (4,6, 50%) 
Colors 
1 2 3 4 5 6 7 8 9 
  
  
Orange} White | Yellow | Brown| Green | White/Sky Blue | Violet | Black | Red 
                
  
  
  
Cheiro Numerology 
1 2 3 |4;5 | 6 8 
A|B{|C;D{|E/]}U|OÑy F 
I K|G|M/H/;}V]{Z|P 
J) RILITJNIJW 
Q S X 
Y 
                    
23 
  
 
Numbers and Colours as per Date of Birth and Dates of destiny. 
Number 1 
AUSPICIOUS NUMBER 1: Born on 1, 10, 19, and 28 of any Month: 
The number comes under the planet SUN. These people have firm view of their 
own. They are busy and adamant. They work only on major things. Usually they don't 
like to work under any one or to be supervised. People usually respect them. Their 
decisions are made of careful thought and study. Once taken decision, they don't change. 
They keep their appointments in time. Whichever field they work they try to reach the 
highest position. They keep the responsibility of taking care of their family. They don't 
like oily and hot food. They are fond of spiritual books. They have firm belief in god. 
They like soft songs. They have control on others and respect too. Leadership qualities 
are high. They are of independent nature. Their advice proves to be beneficial to others. 
They earn lot of money through their intelligence. They never lack confidence. They are 
straightforward, honest, and bright. They have endless energy and enthusiasm. They are 
tending to be lonelier. They lack in diplomacy and need to get along with others. They go 
to bed late Careers like designing, politics, government related jobs, medicine, arts, 
management, inventing, planning, teaching, leadership and writing is involved. They 
have to take care of their heart, poor blood circulation and eyes. Lucky direction isEast 
and lucky days are Sunday and Monday. 
Lucky dates in a Month: 1, 2, 4, 7, 10, 11, 13, 16, 19, 20, 22, 25, 29 and 31. 
Economic Prosperity years: 1, 10, 19, 28, 37 and 46. 
1: Those having their DOB as 1 are usually not tall. 
10: Those having their DOB as 10 are taller. 
19: Those having their DOB as 19 are tall and handsome. They would be designated in 
Government job and in the highest position. They are trustworthy and maintain personal 
cleanliness. They give importance to Love and Affection. 
28: Those having their DOB as 28 are usually not tall. They are fickle-minded, they 
mingle with everybody easily. Their life progress is slow. 
(GemùRuby, GrainùWheat) 
1------ 1 --1,3,4,5,9 Orange, Yellow, Brown, Green, Red. 
1------ 2 --3,5,7 Yellow, Green. 
1------ 3 --1,3,4,5,9 Orange, Yellow, Red. 
1------ 4 --1,3,9 Yellow, Orange, Red. 
24
1------ 5 --1,5,9 Green, Orange, Red. 
1------ 6 --4,5,9 Brown, Green, Red. 
1------ 7 --1,4,7 Orange, Brown, White. 
1------ 8 --3,5,9 Yellow, Green, Red. 
1------ 9 --3,4,5,9 Yellow, Brown, Green, Red. 
Number 2 
AUSPICIOUS NUMBER: Born on 2, 11, 20, and 29 of any Month: 
The number comes under the planet MOON. These people are polite. They are 
sensitive and if someone insults, they take it to their heart. They internally do not accept 
others views and don't oppose them too. They are the best analyzers of others. They love 
art, imagination, emotional and lovers of beauty. They admire nature a lot. They are 
fickle minded and cannot take firm decisions. They think over a plan too much and more 
or less don't bring into practice. During sleep their thoughts don't stop. They lack 
attention when others ask and ask to repeat. They have huge attraction for water. They 
save water and get irritated if no water at home. They get frustrated soon and need to 
develop confidence and courage. They are revolutionary, quick in decision but not firm 
and sometime dictatorial attitude. They are usually non-violent. They always think of 
success. These people are always engaged in some work or the other. They are fast in 
talking, reading and writing. They are romantic too. They are self-inspired and 
motivated. They get frustrated instantly and sometimes lose their cool. They always need 
partner for fresh energy and courage. They rather quickly believe others and get cheated 
often. They like fast and rhythmic songs. They like salty and bitter food. They like curry 
foods and fruits a lot. These people understand the grief of others and become too 
emotional. They always think of well being of others. They please others immediately. 
They like the company of many people and tend to meet new friends. They are 
diplomatic, creative, intuitive and emotional. Careers like agriculture, advertising, film 
industry, travel job, painting, poetry, architecture, computers, photography, printing, 
writing, liquid business, textiles, clothing, jewelry and gems. They have to take care of 
cough, cold, indigestion, gas trouble, intestinal disease, tumors, eyes, lymphatic vessels 
and drinking. Lucky direction is North West and lucky days are Sunday, Monday and 
Friday. 
Lucky dates in a Month: 1, 2, 4, 7, 10, 11, 13, 16, 19, 20, 22, 25, 28 and 29. 
Economic Prosperity years: 2, 11, 20, 25, 29, 35, 38, 47 and 56. 
2: Those having their DOB as 2 do not follow suggestions from others. They possess 
misconduct and have the worst speech. They are secretive in nature. 
11: Those having their DOB as 11 possess the characteristics of their parents (as there is 
25
mingling of Moon and Sun). They talk less and work more and do good to the society. 
They face insult and difference of opinion in the family. Their health is in good condition. 
20: Those having their DOB as 20 have a good physique, soft mind and they possess the 
nature to bring about change. They are talkative and possess skill and intelligence. 
29: Those having their DOB as 29 are egoistic and have no observation of their speech as 
Moon and Mars are together. They always take lead to help others. 
(Gem ù Pearl and Grain ù Rice) 
2------ 1 --3,5,7 Yellow, Green, Blue. 
2------ 2 --3,5,6,7 White, Green, Yellow, Blue. 
2------ 3 --2,3 White, Yellow. 
2------ 4 --3,6,7 Yellow, White, Blue. 
2------ 5 --5,6 Green, White, Blue. 
2------ 6 --2,5,6 White, Green, Blue. 
2------ 7 --2,7,6 White, Blue. 
2----- 8 --3,5,6 Yellow, Green, White. 
2-----9 --1,3,5,6 Yellow, Green, Red. 
Number 3 
AUSPICIOUS NUMBER 3: Born on 3, 12, 21 and 30 of any Month: 
The number comes under the planet JUPITER. They are logical people. They like 
to rule over others. They don't want others to rule over them. They think themselves great 
compared to others in any area of their life. They are intelligent, tolerant, ambitious, 
energetic, talented and punctual. They are particular about work. They work to reach 
high in life with rules. They like to lead a luxurious life and tend to purchase costly items. 
They please their friends and relatives. They don't want complaints on them from any 
one. No one should control them. They don't like to work under domination. They are 
disciplined in work and are fearless. They like rich and big people and adore being like 
them and working. They don't accept anybody so easily. The like music very much. They 
sometimes are ruthless on others. They like to fight odds during difficult times. They are 
poor planners of money and tend to run out of it soon. They should control expenditure 
and save for old age. They should control their egoistic nature. They should avoid 
jealousy. They like hot oily and spicy food. Careers like politics, public offices, banking, 
advertising, acting teaching, medicine suits. They are prone to skin, nerves, spinal cord, 
leg pain and diabetes. Lucky direction is North East and lucky days are Tuesday, 
Thursday and Friday. 
26
Lucky dates in a Month: 3, 10, 12, 18, 19, 21, 27 and 30. 
Economic Prosperity years: 6, 15, 21, 24, 30, 33, 39, 48 and 57. 
3: Those having their DOB as 3 are the most active; they talk less and work more. They 
possess the habit of collecting and processing and are of struggling nature. The usually 
have more number of daughters. It is good to them if Jupiter is in its position. They 
should not have the habit of consuming alcohol. They face difficulty if they got fat. 
12: Those having their DOB as 12 possess the characteristics of their parents. They 
provide a lot of suggestions to others and the suggestion is intellectual. They possess 
helping nature. They lead a constant lifestyle. 
21: Same points as in DOB 12 are applicable for the ones having their DOB as 21. 
30: Those having their DOB as 30 possess the characteristics to bring about change. 
They lose consistency often. They tend to struggle in their life as it is the last date of the 
month. 
(Gem - Pushyaraga, Grain-Bengal Gram) 
3------ 1 --1, 3,9 Orange, Yellow, Red. 
3------ 2 --2, 3 White, Yellow. 
3------ 3 --1, 2,3, 8,9 Orange, White, Yellow, Red, Blue. 
3------ 4 --1,3,9 Yellow, Red. Orange. 
3------ 5 --1, 2, 8,9 White, Orange, Red. 
3------ 6 --2, 4, 8,9 Brown, Blue, White, Red. 
3------ 7 --1,2,4 Orange, White, Brown. 
3------ 8 --3,9 Yellow, Red. 
3------ 9 --1, 3, 4, 8, 9 Orange, Yellow, Brown, Blue, Red. 
Number 4 
AUSPICIOUS NUMBER 4: Born on 4, 13, 22, and 31 of any Month: 
The number comes under the planet RAHU. These people are trustworthy, have 
stamina, dependable and inventive. The natures of these people are different from others. 
They study a subject very deeply. They suffer from opposition. They usually have more 
number of enemies. They are strong willed and usually nontraditional and practical. 
27
They never change opinion and not bother even if they suffer loss. Their anger is high 
and beyond control. Friendship with these people is not easy. They do have very few 
friends. They cannot adjust anybody in their family. These people are mysterious too. 
They don't like to amass wealth, but wealth flows easily towards them. They use it in a 
constructive way and sometimes stingy. These people have to develop common sense, 
balance of mind and self-confidence and emotions. They oppose customs and traditions 
and debate on it. They are studious and interested in public welfare. These people are not 
interested in self-importance and are very principled and idealistic. They have sharp 
eyesight. They are extreme in their thoughts and inspection oriented mind. They 
maintain highest secrets with them. Their friendship doesn't last for long. They should 
avoid criticizing others. They should avoid smoking and drinking, may lead to addicts. 
They seldom love music and go to extreme if interested. Careers like astrology, stock 
market, hotels, constructions, publishing, research, management, transport suits. They 
are prone to depression, urinary infections, unexplained illness, poor respiratory, 
anemia, mental illness and colds. Lucky direction is East and lucky days are Sunday, 
Monday and Saturdays. 
Lucky dates in a Month: 1, 2, 4, 7, 10, 11, 13, 16, 19, 20, 22, 25, 28 and 29. 
Economic Prosperity years: 13, 19, 22, 28, 31, 37, 40, 46, 49, 55 and 58. 
4: Those having their DOB as 4 are angry by nature and possess the intention of taking 
revenge. Their speech and target is the same. They are not defeated by others. They are 
slim and handsome. They are ofhelping nature. 
13: Those having their DOB as 13 are healthy and intelligent. They decline suggestions 
from others as their Zodiacal sign head is Rahu. They are of helping nature and are 
committed towards Love and Affection. 
22: Those having their DOB as 22 are fickle-minded and have no consistency. They 
have no development. They do not have a good physique and often fall sick. 
31: Those having their DOB as 31 are highly intelligent and healthy. They accept 
suggestions from others. 
(Gem ùGomedhaka, Grainù Black Gram) 
4------ 1 --1,3,7,9 Orange, Yellow, Red. 
4------ 2 --3,6,7 Yellow, Blue. 
4------ 3 --1,3 Orange, Yellow. 
4------ 4 --1,3,6,7,9 Orange, Blue, Yellow, Red. 
4------ 5 --1,6,9 Orange, Blue, Red. 
28
4------ 6 --6,7,9 Blue, Red. 
4------ 7 --1,6 Orange, Blue. 
4------ 8 --3,6,9 Yellow, Blue, Red. 
4------ 9 --1,3,6 Orange, Blue, Yellow. 
Number 5 
AUSPICIOUS NUMBERS: Born on 5, 14 and 23 of any Month: 
The number comes under the planet MERCURY. These people like to form more 
friends. They are sensuous, emotional, changeable and impulsive. They have a unique 
sense of humor while talking. They talk freely and clearly. They have the ability to read 
others fast. They are always in a hurry in their work. They are good of completion work 
soon. They have tendency of mind to become rich quickly. They are more attracted to any 
money increasing schemes. Their memory is excellent. They can reach to top position by 
using their intellect and their memory is very good. They are good at leading masses and 
in speech. Their main aim is to acquire knowledge. They work vigorously and guide the 
people. They should have firm mind and should not the fickle. They make critical 
decisions easy with logic. They are inclined to material interests. They have the ability to 
hypnotize other in no time. They reach top position in small period by not wasting time. 
They usually have liking for multiple profession. They look young compared to their 
actual age. They like soft music. Careers like business, writing, communication, 
astrology, statistics, travel job, journalism, debates, shares, drama, education, trading, 
banking public relation and computers. They are prone to skin disorder nervous 
disability, insomnia, paralysis, spinal cord and digestive system. Lucky direction is 
North and lucky days are Wednesday and Friday. 
Lucky dates in a Month: 5, 6, 8, 14, 15, 17, 23, 24 and 26. 
Economic Prosperity Years: 14, 15, 17, 23, 24, 26, 32, 33, 38, 41, 42, 44, 50, 51, 53, 59 
and 60. 
5: Those having their DOB as 5 are soft and possess good conduct. They have a good 
wisdom. They possess great skill and intelligence. Mercury supports them in their 
wisdom and business. As Lord Vishnu is the head of Number 5, they manage all their 
affairs with utmost skill and determination and perform their work in time and with 
intelligence. Thus, those who are born on this date, are naturally intelligent and educated 
and earn from where they are. 
14: Those having their DOB as 14 possess good conduct and are of the noblest 
personality as the Number | is of Sun and Number 4 is headed by Rahu. Also, as there is 
Rahu, they will have the worst times from it. 
29
23: Those having their DOB as 23 possess good mind power and yoga strength. So, their 
way of thinking is special because the head of Number 2 is Moon and the head of 
Number 3 is Jupiter. The heads of both the planets are special. They possess guiding 
nature and intelligence. The structure of their body is of dual type. Such people always 
do good to others and provide good suggestions to others. It is good to be intimate with 
such people but it is harmful to be not intimate with them. Such people get success after 
their age of 32 years. 
(Gem-Emerald/ Peridot, Grain-Green Gram) 
5------ 1 --1,5,9 Orange, Green, Red, White. 
5------ 2 --2,6 White, Green, Blue. 
5------ 3 --1,2,8,9 White, Orange, Red. 
5------ 4 --1,6,9 Orange, Red, White, Blue. 
5------ 5 --1,2,6,8,9 White, Red, Green. 
5------ 6 -- 2,5, 6,8,9 Blue, Red, Green, White. 
5------ 7 --1,2,6 White, Blue, Orange. 
5------ 8 --5,6,9 Green, Red, Blue, White. 
5------ 9 --1,5,6,8,9 White, Orange, Green, Red, Blue. 
Number 6 
AUSPICIOUS NUMBER 6: Born on 6, 15 and 24 of any Month: 
The number comes under the planet VENUS.They always feel to have a clean 
image. They respect others and get respect from others. They have good attraction. They 
don't change their path of life easily and stick to one routine. They like lot of social work. 
They like to get to the highest post in any field they work. These people plan their tasks 
skillfully. They are restless to finish any work they undertake. They have lasting 
friendship and maintain them for life. They are usually fond of pets. They don't like to 
quarrel with any one. They are charitable, romantic, idealistic, sensual, true lovers and 
good character. They should avoid from being addicts of any sort. They are always busy 
in achieving their goal. They like singing and old songs. They don't like obligations from 
other. They get the secrets of other by conversation. They should avoid revengeful 
attitude. These people are lovers of nature and beauty. If they accept any views they go to 
extent of sacrifice on it. They should avoid adamant nature. Career like institution heads, 
commerce, medicine, textile, entertainment, spiritual, architecture, military, fashion, 
30
hotels and interior designing. They are prone to heart, generative organs, tonsils, ear, 
nose, liver and lungs. Lucky direction is South East and lucky days are Tuesday, 
Thursday and Friday. 
Lucky dates in a Month: 3,6, 9, 12, 15, 18, 21, 24, 27 and 30. 
Economic Prosperity years: 15, 20, 24, 26, 33, 35, 39, 42, 44, 47, 51, 53 and 56. 
6: Those having their DOB as 6 possess the personality of creating love and attraction in 
others, towards them as it is the Number of Venus and Venus is interested in beauty. 
Intimacy with such people is good with regards to ornaments, clothes. They are lucky 
people. 
15: Those having their DOB as 15 are healthy and wise. Their intelligence is their capital. 
As the head is Venus, they are beautiful and attractive if they are females. They grab 
everything from others with their intelligence. They possess the ability to overtake, they 
are affectionate and sexual etc. 
24: Those having their DOB as 24 are born with the impact of Number 2 and Number 4. 
Their mind is always fickle. As the head is Venus, and the three planets are female, they 
possess the nature of impressing others with their utmost intelligence and wit. They 
possess a soft nature but a strange behavior. They mingle with everybody and they grab 
whatever is available. They speak attractively but sometimes they fall into problems. At 
such times, it is difficult for them to get rid of their problems. 
(Gem-Diamond / Zircon, Grain-Avare) 
6------ 1 --4,5,7,9 Red, Green, Brown. 
6------ 2 --2,5,6, 7 White, Green, Blue. 
6------ 3 --2,4, 8,9 Red, white, Blue. 
6------ 4 --4,6,7,9 Orange, Red. 
6------ 5 --2,5,6,8,9 White, Green, blue, Red. 
6------ 6 --2,4, 5, 7, 8, 9 White, Green, Blue. 
6------ 7 --2,4,6,7 White, Blue. 
6------ 8 --5,6,9 Red, Green, Blue. 
6------ 9 --4,5,6,9 Red, Green, Blue. 
31
Number 7 
AUSPICIOUS NUMBER 7: Born on 7, 16 and 25 of any Month: 
The number comes under the planet KETU. These people are always looking for a 
change. They are not interested in doing the same thing repeatedly. They love travel a lot. 
They love books, travel and television a lot. They are intuitive, intellectual, psychic and 
unique. They find a job where travel is involved. They have capacity to guide and 
encourage others. They like to have separate identity. They study a lot and also research. 
They spend lot of time in new experiments and research. They try to give advice to others 
and also are proficient in advising. They have inner knowledge, vitality and have 
intuition of future happenings. They come out of difficult situations easily. Failure in 
work depresses them. Due to this they seldom get angry and irritated. These people are 
dreamers and their dream comes true most of the time. Many get attracted to these 
people. Their opinions don't go wrong. They never change their decisions. They have 
capacity to read others mind. They don't get deceived easily. They are messengers to 
others. They like music a lot and get engrossed in it. They are fond of reading. They 
maintain good relations with seniors. They also do social work. These people should 
avoid deep water swimming. They should watch on time and avoid wasting it. They like 
liquid substance like milk and fruit juice. Careers like writers, poets, artists, actors, 
foreign trade, occult, religion and dairy items. They are prone to stomach ailments, 
colds, flu, skin ailments, rheumatism, constipation and blood pressure. Lucky direction 
is North West and lucky days are Sunday, Monday and Friday. 
Lucky dates in a Month: 1, 2, 7, 10, 11, 13, 16, 19, 20, 22, 25, 28 and 29. 
Economic Prosperity years: 7, 11, 16, 20, 25, 29, 34, 38, 43, 47 and 57. 
7: Those having their DOB as 7 are not consistent and cannot take their own decisions in 
life. They are dependent on others. It is suitable for them if they find a job that involves a 
lot of roaming. They should register any of their property in favour of their wives and 
children. They should use silver plates or glass or should wear silver chain on the neck 
and the chain can have an imprint of Lord Ganesh, elephant, horse. Such persons should 
wear clothes having more lines in it. They should not consume food having much of 
chilli and should not consume meat on Full Moon Day and New Moon Day. They should 
not consume eggs on 4" and 7" dates. They show interest in black magic activities. 
16: Those having their DOB as 16 are not consistent even though they have luck and 
health. The defect of the head is the cause for this. They do not have a consistent 
behaviour. Usually they are notrich. They get rich accidentally and hence some of their 
behaviour might change. They spoil their life themselves. 
25: Those having their DOB as 25 have a strong mind power and wisdom. Such people 
contribute much to the society. They lead a satisfactory life with peace, pleasure and 
happiness. They donate and contribute much to orphanages and old age homes with 
kindness. 
32
(Gem ù-Cat's Eye, Grainù Horse Gram) 
ùe 1 --1,4,7 White, Brown, Sky Blue. 
7------ 2 --2,6 White, Sky Blue. 
7]------ 3 --1,2,4 White, Sky Blue, Orange. 
7]------ 4 --1,6 Blue, Brown, Orange. 
7------ 5 --1,2, 6 White, Sky Blue, Orange. 
7------ 6 --2,4,6,7 White, Sky Blue, Brown. 
ù 7 --1,2,4,6 White, Sky Blue, Orange. 
7------ 8 --6 White, Blue. 
7------ 9 --1,4,6 Blue, Orange. 
Number 8 
AUSPICIOUS NUMBER 8: Born on 8, 17 and 26 of any Month: 
The number comes under the planet SATURN. These people think about any 
subject deeply. They strive to get justice equally to all. They are firm about their views. 
They have great love for children. They spend money on them too. These people are 
internally emotional and don't express to others. Their views on many subjects are clear. 
Many times they behave stern sense of justice. Many people don't freely talk with them. 
Usually these people feel lonely. They face opposition and dangers from others. Dharma 
is their main character. They are very secret in what they do. If they develop their mental 
capacity they reach high positions. They don't want to enjoy happiness alone. Their 
attitude is to make social reforms through philosophy. They are engrossed in their own 
thought. These sometimes get into absent mindedness. It's difficult for many people to 
understand others. They are of serious nature. They are firm about their decisions. They 
are honest with their friends. They try to earn money from many sources and spend less. 
They like light food. Careers like law, social work, philosophy, science, religious 
institution, mining, estate agent, iron and steel, finance, footwear, and administration. 
They are prone to headache, skin, gas trouble, leg pain and intestinal trouble. Lucky 
direction is West and lucky days are Sunday, Monday and Saturday. 
Lucky dates in a Month: 5, 6, 8, 14, 15, 17, 23, 24 and 26. 
Economic Prosperity years: 8, 14, 15, 17, 23, 24, 26, 32, 33, 35, 41, 42, 44, 50, 51 and 
53. 
33
8: Those having their DOB as 8 are slow in decision making as the Saturn is head. They 
perform all works partially but there is no completeness in working. It is better for them 
to make friendship with the people having patience and understanding. Problems occur 
suddenly in their life. Their diseases increase. If such person is born in orthodox family, it 
is good for them. They are fast in following lifestyle and they take life challengingly. 
They should not lie and should be as honest as possible. They should have a motto of 
service. They face many problems. They should possess honesty in order to face such 
problems successfully. 
17: Those having their DOB as 17 are straight-forward and courageous and possess 
social motto. They achieve something in their work. They suffer from poverty and 
loneliness throughout their life. They perform illegal activities fearlessly and involve in 
illegal activities that are adverse to the nation. They frighten others. They have fastness 
in their lifestyle. They are not stressed from anything. They cannot be a family holder. 
They always have the fear of arrest. 
26: Those having their DOB as 26 are very fast in working. They are of soft and silent 
nature. They are beautiful but their behavior is rude. It is not good to make friendship 
with them. They are mentally inconsistent even their mental strength is strong. They are 
less in cleanliness. They are addicted to bad habits. They don't want to work as 
subordinate to others. They don't have business for their own. 
(Gem-Blue Sapphire, Grain ù Black Sesame) 
8------ 1 --3,5,9 White, Yellow, Green. 
8------ 2 --3,5,6 Yellow, Green, Blue, White. 
8------ 3 --3,8,9 Red, Yellow. 
8------ 4 --3,6,9 Yellow, Red, Blue. 
8------ 5 --5,6,9 Red, Blue, Green. 
8------ 6 --5,6,9 Red, Blue, Green. 
8------ 7 --6 White, Blue. 
8------ 8 --3,5,6,9 Yellow, Red, Blue, Green. 
8------ 9 --3,5,6 Yellow, Red, Blue, Green. 
34
Number 9 
AUSPICIOUS NUMBER 9: Born on 9, 18 and 27 of any Month: 
The number comes under the planet Mars. They are very ambitious. They are 
bold, moral and quick decision maker. They do not like delaying of any work. These 
people don't like opposition. They have a great presence of mind. They don't like to work 
under anybody. They become reckless and have very little self-control. They face many 
accidents in life. They get injured in routine life. They have a dynamic personality. They 
have quarreling and outspoken nature and hence create many enemies. They like to be 
independent. They don't like any type of control. They are fickle minded to some extent. 
They do not sit still for long hours. They get depressed if they see failure. These people 
make friendship with rich and high position individuals. They spend money freely and 
always don't plan for old age. They face many ups and downs in their life. They have urge 
to see lot of places. They like to lead a speedy life. They have frequent clashes with 
partners. They try to control their partner. They finish their job quickly. They should 
check thoroughly while signing any contract. Family peace depends pure on their 
behavior; hence try to be cool and calm. They should give respect to their partner. They 
like music a lot and like to be singers. Careers like engineering, mining, water, military, 
police, foreign relations, publishing, business and writing suits them. They are prone to 
accidents, bone breakage, skin, gastric trouble, head, teeth and blood circulation. Luck 
direction is South and lucky days are Sunday, Tuesday, Thursday and Friday. 
Lucky dates in a Month: 3, 6, 9, 12, 15, 18, 21, 24, 27 and 30. 
Economic Prosperity years: 9, 18, 21, 27, 30, 36, 39, 45, 48, 54,57 and 63. 
9: Those having their DOB as 9, struggle with bravery and courage for the justice and 
truth. They are alone in their struggle and adventure. Their lifestyle is hard. Their 
behavior is rude. Their conduct is willful. Their family life is not better. They have more 
female children. They possess the attitude of ego and anger. They do not care for 
anybody's advice and they do not honour the appraisal from others. There will be no 
peace and harmony from them in their family. They oppose their parents. Their parents 
will not be with them. 
18: Those having their DOB as 18 follow the way of justice and truth. They advise others, 
the way of life. They should not give their used dresses to anybody. 
27: Those having their DOB as 27 don't like family and there is no peace and harmony in 
their family. They suffer from mental disturbance and inconsistency. They are always 
ready to involve in illegal activities. They get less pleasure from family. They do not 
enjoy pleasure and happiness even if they are rich. 
(Gem-Coral, Grain-Toordal) 
35
9------ 1 --1, 3,4, 5,9 Yellow, Red, Green. 
9------ 2 --3, 5,6 Yellow, Green, Blue. 
9------ 3 --1,3,9 Orange, Yellow, Red. 
9------ 4 --1, 3, 6,9 Yellow, Red, Blue. 
9------ 5 --1, 5, 6, 8,9 Orange, Green, Blue, Red. 
9------ 6 --4, 5, 6,9 Green, Blue, Red. 
9------ 7 --1,4,6 Orange, Sky Blue. 
9------ 8 --3, 5,6 Yellow, Green, Blue, Red. 
9-----9 --1, 3, 4, 5, 6, 8,9 Red, Yellow, Green. 
Marriage Dates 
To those whose birth dates are-1,10,19, 28: - 3,9, 12, 21 
To those whose birth dates are-2,11,20, 29: - 1, 3, 6, 10, 12, 21, 24 
To those whose birth dates are-3, 12, 21,30: - 1, 3, 9, 10, 12, 19 
To those whose birth dates are-4,13, 22, 31: - 1, 6, 9, 10, 19, 24 
To those whose birth dates are-5,14, 23: - 1, 2, 9, 10, 11, 19, 20, 24 
To those whose birth dates are-6,15, 24: - 2, 9, 20, 24 
To those whose birth dates are-7,16,25: - 1, 2, 6, 10, 11, 19, 20, 24 
To those whose birth dates are-8,17, 26: - 3, 6, 9, 24, 30 
To those whose birth dates are-9,18, 27: - 3, 5, 6, 12,14, 15, 21, 23 
36
Mahuthams for HouseùWarming (Own House / Rented House) 
To those whose birth dates are 1, 10, 19, and 28: These persons may perform 
the process of milk boiling and flowing over, from 4-30 a.m. to 6-30 a.m. (Before 
Sunrise). 1, 10, 19/3, 12, 21/4, 13, 22, 31/5, 14, 23 / 9, 27 dates are suitable for the 
process. The milk should boil and flow over. 
To those whose birth dates are 2, 11, 20, and 29: The process of milk raising 
may be performed after 7-30 a.m. and before 6 p.m. The 1, 10/3, 30/5, 14, 23/6, 15, 24 
dates are special. They should perform the process of milk raising in the central hall of 
the house. The bow] containing milk should be sloped towards right-side. The grains of 
Bengal gram, Beans and Green gram should be offered and worshipped in the place of 
worship. 
To those whose birthdays are 3, 12, 21, and 30: 1,10,19/11, 20/3, 12, 21/9, 18, 
27 dates are good. The Muhurtha should not be before or after the New Moon Day 
(Amavasya). There should be the portrait of any Guruji on wall before the main door of 
the house. But the portrait should not be framed with glass. 
To those whose birthdays are 4, 13, 22, and 31: There is special benefit on 6, 15, 
24/9, 27/1, 10, 19 dates are special. There should be the portrait of God Padmanabha, 
being in posture of sleeping, on the wall before the Main Door of the house. From this 
process, the house is relieved from its defects. 
To those whose birthdays are 5, 14, and 23: 1,10,19,28/ 2, 11,20, 29/6, 15,24 
/ 9, 18, 27 dates are special. There should be the portrait of God Laxmi Narayana on the 
wall before the Main Door of the house. Anna Daana and donations to old age homes 
should be given often. 
To those whose birthdays are 6, 15, and 24: 2, 11, 20, 29/5, 14, 23/9, 18, 27 
dates are very good. There should be the portrait of Lord Venkateshwara. 
To those whose birthdays are 7, 16, and 25: 4,13, 22, 31/1, 10,19 /2, 11,20, 29 
/6, 15, 24 dates are special. The process of milk raising should be performed, from 5 am 
to 7 am. For getting richer, there should be the portrait of Lord Ganesha on the wall 
before the Main Door of the house. 
To those whose birthdays are 8, 17, and 26: There should be the idol of Lord 
Anjaneya with posture of meditation before the Main Door of the house. 5, 14, 23/ 6, 15, 
24 dates are special. 
To those whose birthdates are 9, 18, and 27: 1,10,19/ 3,12, 21, 30/5, 14, 23/ 
6, 15,24 are special dates. There should be the portrait of Lord Shanmukha. 
37
Mahurthams for Vehicle Purchase 
If any vehicle is purchased, the last digit of the vehicle No. should not be 0. 2. 7. 4. 8. 
1) 
2) 
3) 
4) 
5) 
6) 
8) 
9) 
DOB 1, 10, 19, 28: While registering vehicle, there should not be 0, 6, 8 in the 
Vehicle No. The sum of the digits in the No. should be 3 or 5. 
DOB 2, 11, 20, 29: While registering vehicle, there should not be 0, 4, 8, 9 in the 
Vehicle No. The sum of the digits in the No. should be 5 or 6. 
DOB 3, 12, 21, 30: While registering vehicle, there should not be 4, 5, 6, 7 in the 
Vehicle No. The sum of the digits in the No. should be 1 or 9. 
DOB 4, 13, 22, 31: While registering vehicle, there should not be 2, 5, 8 in the 
Vehicle No. The sum of the digits in the No. should be 1, 6 or 9. 
DOB 5, 14, 23: While registering vehicle, there should not be 3,4,7 in the Vehicle 
No. The sum of the digits in the No. should be 1, 6 or 9. 
DOB 6, 15, 24: While registering vehicle, there should not be 1, 3, 8 in the Vehicle 
No. The sum of the digits in the No. should be 5 or 9. 
DOB 7, 16, 25: While registering vehicle, there should not be 3, 5, 8, 9 in the 
Vehicle No. The sum of the digits in the No. should be 1, 2 or 6. 
DOB 8, 17, 26: While registering vehicle, there should not be 1, 2, 4, 7 in the 
Vehicle No. The sum of the digits in the No. should be 5 or 6. 
DOB 9, 18, 27: While registering vehicle, there should not be 2, 7, 8 in the Vehicle 
No. The sum of the digits in the No. should be 3, 5 or 6. 
38
1) 
2) 
3) 
4) 
5) 
6) 
8) 
9) 
Mahurthams for Land Worship 
To those who was born on 1, 10, 19, 28: Land worship should be made on 9, 18, 
27 dates. Toordal should be sprinkled on the land. Afterwards the digging may be 
done deeply. 
To those who was born on 2, 11, 20, 29: Land worship should be made before 
sunrise on-6, 15, 24 dates. Afterwards Coconut water should be sprinkled on 
the land. Afterwards the digging may be done deeply. 
To those who was born on 3, 12, 21, 30: Land worship should be made on 3, 9, 
12, 19, 21, 27 dates. Afterwards water brought from Land Well should be 
sprinkled on the land. Afterwards the digging may be done deeply. 
To those who is born on 4, 13, 22, 31: Land worship should be made on 6, 15, 24 
dates.Afterwards water brought from any God's Abhishekam should be 
sprinkled on the land. Afterwards the digging may be done deeply. 
To those who was born on 5, 14, 23: Land worship should be made on 9, 18, 
19, 27 dates. Afterwards the soil brought from the Mars, Anjaneya or Narasimha 
Temple should be sprinkled on the land. Afterwards the digging may be done 
deeply. 
To those who was born on 6, 15, 24: Land worship should be made on 6, 15, 24 
dates. Afterwards the holy water of Abhishekham made in temple related to any 
goddess should be sprinkled on the land. Afterwards the digging may be done 
deeply. 
To those who was born on 7, 16, 25: Land worship should be made on 6, 15, 24 
dates. Then water brought from river should be sprinkled on the land. Afterwards 
the digging may be done deeply. 
To those who was born on 8, 17, 26: Land worship should be made on 5, 14, 26 
dates. Then water brought from Abhishekam done on Shivalingam should be 
sprinkled on the land. Afterwards the digging may be done deeply. 
To those who was born on 9, 18, 27: Land worship should be made on3, 6, 12, 15, 
21, 24 dates. Toordal should be sprinkled on the land. Afterwards the digging may 
be done deeply. 
39
Mahurthams to dig Bore wells 
Lagna of Cancer, Gemini, Capricorn, Libra, Virgo. The worship should be made after 
sprinkling coconut water in the place specified to dig bore well. Full-moon Day is very 
good to dig bore well. The dark half of the Lunar month (Krishna Paksha) is not good for 
this. But the bright half of the Lunar Month (Shukla Paksha) is good. The worship should 
be performed by women. The dates- 2, 11, 20 are good to dig bore well. 
40
Chinese Numerology 
Lo Shu Grid 
  
  
  
          
Lo Shu Grid: 4000 years ago, this grid was introduced in China. This square is 
remarkable because every horizontal, vertical & diagonal row adds up to fifteen. 
1) 
2) 
3) 
4) 
5) 
6) 
7) 
8) 
9) 
    
    
  
  
    
MENTAL we) wil sz 3 6 9 e| 3/3 
3 5 3 EMOTIONAL S =| 5 
PRACTICAL re < 1 4 7 EB   
                
  
  
Good communicator/Hard to express their innermost feelings. 
Sensitive & intuitive. Easy to be hurt. 
Intellectual Capacity, positive attitude happy. Thinking clearly and logically. Find 
hard to listen to others. 
Practical, hardworking, Balance and order. Hard to pay attention to other areas of 
life. 
Balance and emotional stability and freedom. They motivate and inspire others. 
Unnecessary risks to be avoided. 
Creativity, Love, Home and Family. Affects emotionally and Affects their mental 
imbalance. 
Learn lessons through losses; knowledge and wisdom are excellent. Little sad 
lives. 
Attention to detail. Restless working. Fixed views and options. 
Humanitarian, Idealism, ambition. Mixing with people from all walks of society 
is low. 
41
Arrow of Strength (/ ) 
1) Arrow of Determination: 
(Vv) 
  
  
2) Arrow of Compassion: 
  
  (Vv) 
  
3) Arrow of intellect: 
a. 
  
  
          
4) Arrow of emotional balance: 
_| | 
42 
  
  
         
Arrow of Strength (/y ) 
5) Arrow of practicality: 
  
  
        
_| | i 
6) Arrow of planner: 
  
  
   
| 
v) 
7) Arrow of will power: 
  
      
  
    
8) Arrow of actiivity: 
  
  
  
(vw)       
43
Arrow of Weakness (x ) (Any Missing Numbers) 
1) Arrow of indecision: 
(x) 
  
  
2) Arrow of Skepticism: 
  
(x)   
  
3) Arrow of poor memory: 
ae ~ 
  
  
          
4) Arrow of emotional sensitivity: 
Se 
44 
  
  
         
Arrow of Weakness (x ) (Any Missing Numbers) 
5) Arrow of impracticality: 
  
  
        
| | 
6) Arrow of frustration: 
    
  
' x) 
7) Arrow of hesitation: 
  
  
  
      
8) Arrow of non-planner: 
  
  
  
  
      
45
Absence of Numbers 
1 = Lack of Confidence drive & Motivation 
2 = Lack of people skills, insensitive. 
3 = Lack of fun and friends, self-centered. 
4 = Lack of hardwork. 
5 = Lack of change. 
6 = Lack of handling responsibility. 
7 = Lack of philosophy and are impatient. 
8 = Lack of care on money and possessions. 
9 = Lack of compassion and care. 
46
Exploring Personal Years 
Only Date and Month is added to Current Year 
Example:12ó July 1979 <> Current Year 2017 
Hence- 12 (Date) 
07 (Month July) 
+2017. _ 
2036 =2+0+3+6=11=1+1 =2 
Hence Personal Year = 2 
  
1) 
2) 
3) 
4) 
5) 
6) 
7) 
8) 
9) 
Personal Year-1: New starts, More Enthusiasm and Energy. Anything started is 
likely to remain important for a long time. May start many new ventures. 
Personal Year-2: Slow starts, waste of Time & Energy. Year to be patience in all 
aspects. Pleasant time to be calm. 
Personal Year-3: Pleasant, enjoyable year. But hard work is must. Time to make 
new friends, new hobbies. Short lived interest is more. 
Personal Year-4: Year of hard work. Year will be serious, difficult and restricting. 
This is the year of difficulties. 
Personal Year-5: Year of change. Year of new excitements and different. Perfect 
year to change anything unwanted and unhappy. Change in career, home, partner 
or even country. Be prepared for the unexpected things. Impossible things might 
happen. 
Personal Year-6: Year for home and family. It is a year for separation and 
marriage. It is a year for good or bad. It is a two-way year. If relationship is good, 
this is a wonderful year. If the relationship is bad it is a bad year. Your thoughts and 
energies will be towards home and the people you love. 
Personal Year-7: This is a soft, gentle and quite year. You need more time 
yourself to think. New learning or Education help. Knowledge and wisdom is 
acquired. Spiritual growth expected rather than material possessions. Interested in 
developing inner consciousness. 
Personal Year-8: It is a year of hard work and it is money time. You reap the 
rewards for all the hard works done over the past few years. Health issues may 
occur; have to be cautious. 
Personal Year-9: This is the final year in the wheel of Personal Year Number. 
Letting go off fast things may be a painful and difficult task. You will also be 
looking forward as to where to move ahead. False leads may come in your way. 
Last three months give a clear picture for next nine years. 
47
This is to certify that the Quality Management System of 
rye 
UNIVERSAL 
REGISTRARS 
_ W/S GOLD TREE ASTRO e 
has been assessed and found to conform to the requirements of 
ee 
2015 ISO 9001:2015 
For the following scope: 
Provision for astrology certiflcation courses and astrology 
consultation. 
Certiz, em LEM e See 
R 
ISO 9001:2015 
ù 
o) =) ep) 
o) 
A 
Certifleate number: 25216 
This certiflcate is valid from 07-Nov-2016 until 07-Nov-2019 
and remains valid subject to satisfactory surveillance audits 
on 06-Nov-2017 and 06-Nov-2018. 
Re-certiflcation audit due on 07-Nov-2019. 
Certiflcation expiry on 06-Nov-2019. 
David Wilmer 
Certiflcation Manager 
UNIVERSAL REGISTRARS 
www.universalregistrars.com Æ 
This certificate can be verified at the above URL. as LR << 
The certificate remains the property of Universal Registrars, to whom it : 
must be returned on request. Lack of fulfillment of certification terms z 
and conditions at all times, may render this certificate invalid. 
 
